const QuizData = [
  {
    question: "What is the correct syntax for including a header file in C++?",
    options: [
      "#include <header.h>",
      "#include 'header.h'",
      "include <header.h>",
      "import header.h",
    ],
    answer: 0,
  },
  {
    question: "Which of the following is NOT a C++ data type?",
    options: ["int", "float", "char[]", "boolean"],
    answer: 3,
  },
  {
    question: "What is the operator used for the modulus division in C++?",
    options: ["%", "/", "%%", "mod"],
    answer: 0,
  },
  {
    question: "In C++, what keyword is used to define a class?",
    options: ["class", "define", "struct", "public"],
    answer: 0,
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which C++ loop is used to execute a block of code repeatedly as long as a condition is true?",
    options: ["for loop", "while loop", "do-while loop", "if statement"],
    answer: 1,
  },
  {
    question: "What is the purpose of 'cin' in C++?",
    options: [
      "To include a header file",
      "To output data to the console",
      "To input data from the user",
      "To define a class",
    ],
    answer: 2,
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which of the following is an example of a preprocessor directive in C++?",
    options: [
      "int main() { }",
      "#define PI 3.1415",
      "cout << 'Hello';",
      "while (true) { }",
    ],
    answer: 1,
  },
  {
    question: "What is the default access modifier for members of a C++ class?",
    options: ["private", "public", "protected", "static"],
    answer: 0,
  },
  {
    question: "What does the 'new' operator do in C++?",
    options: [
      "Deletes a variable",
      "Creates a new class",
      "Allocates memory for an object",
      "Returns the size of an array",
    ],
    answer: 2,
  },
  {
    question: "In C++, how do you declare a pointer?",
    options: ["&ptr;", "*ptr;", "#ptr;", "ptr()"],
    answer: 1,
  },
];

export default QuizData;
